Oyindamola Oyebade

Cell: (571) 398-8321 ~ Email: eoyebadeo24@gmail.com ~ Bristow, VA

Objective

Highly motivated front-end developer with a passion for designing visually appealing and user-friendly web applications. Experienced in delivering projects on time and within budget, utilizing modern technologies such as JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Git, React, and Node.js. Possess strong communication skills and the ability to work effectively in a client-facing environment. Dedicated to staying up-to-date with industry advancements and continuously improving development skills, with a focus on delivering high-performing, user-friendly solutions.

Software/Technical Skills

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, SQL, PHP, TypeScript, JSON, Bootstrap, C#

Frameworks/Databases: AngularJS, Vue.js, Node.js, jQuery, ReactJS

Education

Master of Science, Software Development Boston University | Boston, MA

Bachelor of Science, Information Systems

Virginia Commonwealth University | Richmond, VA

Professional Experience

WordPress Designer

Consultant – Bristow, VA

January 2022 – Present

- Creating a user-friendly online catering website using **PHP**, **CSS**, and **MySQL**, utilizing the **WordPress** platform to ensure optimal functionality.
- Successfully managing client's expectations by leading regular clients and project team meetings to establish website requirements and closely monitoring project progress and budget, while providing clear status updates to clients.
- Oversaw the support and maintenance of the systems and applications. Oversee and perform security and software updates to systems, applications, and plugins.
- Designing and implementing compelling, creative, and user-focused experiences that align with the client's business objectives.

Website Content Engineer

YouDecide – Glen Allen, VA

July 2021 – December 2021

- Assisted project managers, designers, and other developers in the planning and migration of content from existing websites into company-based content management systems, utilizing **HTML**, **CSS**, and **JavaScript**.
- Collaborated with client-facing business analysts to execute consistent changes to the front end of the website. These changes helped increase web traffic by over 70%.
- Supported the development of website backends, including customizing taxonomies, fields, database configuration, and integrating external **APIs** in the company's content management system.

Web Content Associate

National Democratic Institute (NDI) – Washington, DC

March 2021 – April 2021

- Promoted strong customer relations with regular client interaction, website reviews, documentation of client's requirements, design, and other information.
- Collaborated with senior front-end developers and content producers to bring the vision of strategists, designers, and creators to life.
- Conducted regression analysis to evaluate the correlation between company content and industry trends, resulting in a 15% improvement in the accuracy of performance prediction compared to previous years.

Front-End Developer

Consultant – Bristow, VA

June 2020 – February 2021

- Accountable for designing, developing, and continuously improving web pages and sites for optimal performance.
- Worked closely with both technical and non-technical stakeholders to gather and explain business requirements.

- Conducted comprehensive search engine optimization (**SEO**) activities to improve the visibility and ranking of client websites, resulting in increased online presence and organic traffic.
- Developed and maintained a user guide to help clients understand site features and management of the website, increasing visitor satisfaction by 60%.

Web Developer

Veriheal – Alexandria, VA

July 2018 - August 2019

- Lead development of a company standard operating procedures (SOP) manual for backend developers.
- Conducted PHP data remediation on the MYSQL database for company backend infrastructure.
- Conducted thorough client-side performance testing prior to every website launch to ensure optimal user experience.
- Successfully added new, innovative front-end features to enhance the functionality and user experience of existing websites.